     Welcome to the help file of the best program for you in this moment!


	                 Statistic Simple v.1.003
// ------------------------------------------------------------------------
           This application only be used for educational aims.
// ------------------------------------------------------------------------
The application was made in purpouses of course mathematical statistics of
second year education for the Tashkent branch of Moscow State University. 

This program gets selection of numbers, creates an interval variational 
series {[a[i],a[i+1]), 0 <= i < sqrt(quantity of numbers)},
defines central number in each interval {x[i]}, counts absolute {n[i]}
and relational {Ʋ[i]} frequencies, amount of data {number in last row n[i]}
and relational frequencies ΣƲ[i]. Also it constructs poligon, histogram and
experiential distribution function, calculates numerical characteristics
of derived assignment.

Quick start:

1.	Use menu 'File' or 'CTRL+O' to open text file to calculate.
2.	Latter You'll see Dialog asking You to select the sign, which
	separates integer part from fractional one of numbers in input file.
3.	If You have chosen incorrect file or made a mistake in Dialog,
	You can repeat first two steps.
	Else You can see that the form has a partition into two areas: 
	on the  left there is place for graphics,
	on the right there is numerical data in tables.
	There is interval variational series in table above, and there is
	Assignment's characteristics in table below.
4.	There are 3 CheckBoxes with lettering on program plane.
	First and second CheckBoxes show You the 'Poligon' and 'Histogram'
	accordingly and can be checked simultaneously.
	The third one shows 'Distribution Function' as scale of it is differ
	from other graphics it can only be checked alone.
	You'll make sure it in practice.
5.	You can selest color of each graphic using submenu 'Color' in 'File'
	or 'CTRL+L'. It can be useful to get more contrast image on print.	
6.	To send received data to printer there is a submenu 'Print' in menu 
	'File' or there is a hot key 'CTRL+P'. If You have a printer device,
	this action starts printing and you get some pages with graphics and
	tables. Program calculates quantity of pages itself, it depends on
	number of intervals and modes.
7.	To get additional information about program there is 'Help' menu or
	'CTRL+H' with 'ReadMe' and 'About' submenus. 
	You have found it, I think, if You read this text.

	Thank you for using our project!

// ------------------------------------------------------------------------
Created by students Tashkent branch MSU AM&I Golikov.K and Zharinov.A.
                             [msu.uz] 2011